CHUN WANG

Software Engineer I Creative Technologist

www.chunwang.me chunwang.me@gmail.com (571) 315-0540

I am an experienced software developer with a keen eye for design. I have 5+ years of experience designing and developing complex web applications and a track record of bridging my creative and technical skills to deliver delightful user experiences that scale to large data.

EDUCATION

Stanford University

Stanford, CA / June 2019

Master of Science in Computer Science GPA: 3.97/4.0

University of Virginia

Charlottesville, VA / May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Minor in Applied Math GPA: 3.91/4.0 (cumulative), 3.95/4.0 (major)

SKILLS

Programming

Python, Java, C++, JavaScript (React, Angular, Vue, Node.js, Express, D3, TypeScript), HTML/CSS Solid knowledge about web technologies and frameworks

Design & Prototyping

Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, Arduino, Processing, openFrameworks

Developer & Build Tools

Git, Jenkins, Gradle, Sonar, Selenium, Webpack, Amazon Web Services

Data Management & Analysis

Familarity with data storage systems, scalability, statistics, machine learning tools and data visualization techniques

ACTIVITIES

Artist & Webmaster@ CODAME ART+TECH
Mentor@ Computers4Kids
Volunteer@ Gray Area Foundation For The Arts

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Amazon
 Palo Alto, CA

 Software Engineer
 8/2019 – present

 Software Engineer Intern
 6/2018 – 9/2018

- Built and launched a new backend query engine utilizing Amazon Athena to improve query performance over large-scale (100TBs~) Amazon Advertising datasets. This improvement reduced end-to-end query latency from previously 20+ minutes to under 10 seconds, enabling an interactive query experience for our customers.
- Built data validation and metadata tracking service to ensure data quality among query datasets
- Designed and implemented web front-end features to keep users informed about query status.

 AppDynamics (now part of Cisco)
 San Francisco, CA

 Senior Software Engineer
 9/2016 – 9/2017

 Software Engineer II
 8/2015 – 9/2016

 Software Engineer I
 7/2014 – 8/2015

- Delivered multiple top-priority front-end projects for the company's flagship Application
 Performance Monitoring product, with interactive widgets, dashboards, streaming
 graphs, live user sessions and other types of data visualization components that scaled
 to large data. Heavily involved in full cycle of product development from product concept
 inception, UX design, API design, to code execution and maintenance.
- Added new components to company's UI component library and optimized existing ones. Experienced in architecting large-scale front-end UI projects.
- Led cross-team initiatives to improve UI performance and code test coverage.
 Established team standards for writing UI unit tests and end-to-end automation tests using Selenium. Worked with build system to support code modularity.
- · Helped hire the team and onboard junior developers.

Curiosity Media

Arlington, VA

Software Engineer Intern

6/2013 - 8/2013

- Designed and implemented audio/video playback, speech recording and recognition, interactive feedback features for www.spanishdict.com, the world's leading Spanish reference website (10 million unique visitors/month).
- Partnered with UX designer to implement and launch the marketing website for a new education product, Fluencia.
- Developed internal tools to track and analyze site visitor data, result leading to UX improvement of product landing pages and boost in conversion rate to 40% on desktop and 22% on mobile devices, from the initial 13% and 5% respectively.

Center for Open Science

Charlottesville, VA

Software Engineer / Research Intern

8/2013 - 5/2014

- Designed and implemented web interface supporting navigation, search and multifaceted filtering in Open Science Framework, a research project management platform that promotes open-access scientific publishing.
- Created interactive visualizations of large-scale research data to facilitate discovery of collaboration opportunities among scientists.
- Conducted social study on incentive structure of online Open Science community.

NSF-REU Program in Data Intensive Computing

Clemson, SC

Undergraduate Researcher

6/2012 - 7/2012

Researched and applied machine learning algorithms to automatically detect epilepsyrelated neural activities in clinical EEG recordings at ~4,400 signals/sec.